Erin Ramos

Alpharetta, GA | (770) 630-7122 | erinramos415@gmail.com | https://github.com/Erin-Ramos

Professional Summary

Motivated Full Stack JavaScript Developer and Marine Corps Veteran with a strong background in mathematics and a passion for problem-solving. Comprehensive experience in web development, including front-end and back-end technologies. Proven ability to develop and deploy full-stack applications using JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3, SQL

• Front-End: React, Redux, AJAX, jQuery

• Back-End: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs

Databases: MongoDB, SQL

• Tools & Platforms: Git, GitHub, npm

• Version Control: Git

Projects

Static Node.js and Express Site:

- https://erinramosportfolio-resume.up.railway.app/
- Developed a static portfolio site using Node.js and Express.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express, HTML, CSS

Full Stack App with React and REST API:

- Integrated React front-end with a RESTful API back-end to create a full-stack application.
- Technologies: React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB

Public API Requests:

- Integrated public APIs to fetch and display data dynamically.
- Technologies: JavaScript, AJAX, JSON

SQL Library Manager:

- Created a library management system with SQL.
- Technologies: SQL, Node.js, Express

React Gallery App:

- Built a photo gallery application using React.
- Technologies: React, CSS, HTML

OOP Game Show App:

- Designed a game show app using Object-Oriented Programming.
- Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Interactive Form:

- Built a dynamic form with real-time validation.
- Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Data Pagination and Filtering:

- Created an app to paginate and filter a list of student data.
- Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Random Quote Generator:

- Developed an application that displays a random quote upon button click.
- Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Education

Team Treehouse

Full Stack JavaScript TechDegree | September 2023 - June 2024

Harvard University, Extension School

Cambridge, MA | Coursework in Computer Science and Mathematics | 2018 - 2019

Bunker Hill Community College

Boston, MA | Associate of Science in Mathematics | 2019 - 2020

Professional Experience

Berkshire Hathaway HomeServices Realtor | 2021 - Present

*United States Marine Corps*Maintenance Management Chief | 2013 - 2017

Certifications

Full Stack JavaScript TechDegree | Team Treehouse